Aashiq Shaikh

Graphics Programmer

■ US Citizen ♣ he/him ► work@aashiqshaikh.com

408-478-1700
▶ Portfolio in LinkedIn Github

PROFILE

AR/VR Application and Graphics Engineer with 5 years of experience building and publishing AR/VR applications. Excited about designing and developing visuals for immersive spatial experiences. Looking for development positions in computer graphics and rendering. (pronounced AH-shik)

EXPERIENCE

AR/VR Graduate Researcher, *Meteor Studio* □

Jan 2020 - Aug 2023 | Tempe, AZ

Developed and led AR/VR development for several multidisciplinary projects in collaboration with meteorology, criminology, film, sustainability and theater departments. Developed visual effects and technical artistry skills. Also managed/mentored 25+ undergraduate students in AR/VR development across all projects.

VR Graphics Programmer, Dreamscape Immersive

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022 | Los Angeles, CA

Worked on a production narrative VR experience, developing artist and programmer facing tools to speed up development. I used HLSL and C# in the Unity environment and regularly worked with low-level shader code to develop a ray marcher and landscape mesh editing tools.

AR/VR Unity Developer, Emblematic Group

Feb 2022 - Mar 2023 | Los Angeles, CA

Led the technical development of a historical narrative AR experience. I worked in the Unity engine and use HLSL and C#. Prototyped new volumetric video technologies and worked with 3D artists to optimize asset rendering.

AR Application Development Intern,

National Center for Atmospheric Research

May 2019 - Aug 2019 | Boulder, CO

Developed a framework to create AR climate-related news articles that could be viewed with a mobile device.

AR/VR Undergraduate Researcher, Meteor Studio 🖸

Jan 2017 - Dec 2019 | Tempe, AZ

Starting as a freshman, I worked as a student researcher for Meteor Studio. I developed my skills in AR/VR development, project management, and technical art. I published a paper on a programmable location-based AR data visualization framework (see **Publications**).

EDUCATION

Media Arts and Sciences, M.A., Arizona State University

2020 - 2021 | Tempe, AZ

GPA: 3.93

Computer Science, B.S., Arizona State University

2016 - 2019 | Tempe, AZ

Provost's Award Recipient, Dean's List for 7 consecutive semesters. GPA: 3.92

REFERENCES

References available upon request.

PROJECTS

Volumetric Video Streaming

Developed a pipeline for capturing, streaming, and rendering volumetric content in AR/VR. I specialized in the data representation and rendering components of the framework. Used Unity, .NET Core, HLSL, and Azure Kinect.

Illumination Estimation for Photorealistic AR Content on Mobile Devices, GLEAM ☑

I streamlined illumination estimation algorithms with compute shaders to take advantage of GPU parallelization, and created applications that utilized this framework. I also added support for multiple AR platforms. Used Unity, ARKit, ARFoundation, and HLSL.

AR Framework for Map-based Immersive Data Visualization, Coordinate ☑

Designed and developed an AR mobile application/framework that augments a physical map with visualizations of location-based data using user-created data spreadsheets. I worked with our university's executive office to design this as a presentation tool for investor meetings. Used Unity, Vuforia, and HLSL.

CPU Ray Tracer Walkthrough

Developing a CPU ray tracer in C++ to validate my understanding of the graphics pipeline from the ground up and break down all the math involved.

PUBLICATIONS

Adaptive 5G systems for interactive volumetric sports analysis in augmented reality, ACM MobiSys ☑

2022

Received Best Demo Award at MobiSys 2022

Characterizing real-time dense point cloud capture and streaming on mobile devices, ACM HotEdgeVideo @ MobiCom ☑

001

Coordinate: A Spreadsheet-Programmable Augmented Reality Framework for Immersive Map-Based Visualizations, IEEE AIVR ☑ 2019

► TECHNICAL SKILLS

AR/VR Development (Unity, ARKit, Oculus, Azure Kinect, Volumetric Video)

Graphics Programming (HLSL, C, C++, Graphics Pipeline, Linear Algebra)

Media Production (Blender, Logic Pro, Illustrator, Photoshop, Final Cut Pro)